# Ducarmel Rodchild Zephyr 613 501 0347

rodchild@gmail.com; http://rodchild.github.io/resume/portfolio.html

https://github.com/rodchild; http://ca.linkedin.com/in/ducarmel

# **Career Objective**

More than 3 years of IT experience with strong technical skill-set. Understanding of responsive design principles and performance as proven by portfolio. I am looking for a Front-End Web Developer role with the opportunity to work with technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript on challenging and diverse projects.

#### Skills

Programming Languages : HTML & CSS (including Bootstrap), JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML5

Canvas, C/C++/C#, SQL.

Frameworks : JavaScript Web App Frameworks (Knockout), JavaScript Testing

Frameworks (Jasmine).

Operating Systems : Linux, Windows.

Other : Sublime Text, Git, Critical Rendering Path, 60FPS Rendering,

Object-Oriented Programming, Chrome Developer Tools.

# **Projects**

#### A PDF-file design mockup has been replicated in HTML and CSS.

• Developed a responsive website using responsive web design principles and responsive images.

#### Online resume using JavaScript and jQuery.

- Mastered the language's syntax through a series of challenges.
- Wrote clean code and used object oriented programming techniques and principles.
- Successfully rendered a resume with an interactive map.

#### Classic Arcade Game Clone using Object-Oriented JavaScript and HTML5 Canvas.

- Recreated the classic arcade game Frogger.
- Added player character and enemies to received visual assets and game loop engine.

# Website Performance and Browser Rendering Optimization.

- Optimized a provided website with some optimization and performance related issues.
- Achieved a target PageSpeed score and run at 60 frames per second.

# **Neighborhood Map using AJAx and JavaScript Design Patterns.**

- Developed a single-page application featuring a map of my neighborhood.
- Added map markers to identify popular locations or places I'd like to visit.
- Added search function and listview to support simple browsing of all locations.
- Researched and implemented third-party APIs that provide location additional information.

# Feed Reader Testing using JavaScript Testing.

Created successful test.

# **Relevant Experience**

### Web developer

April 2012 - September 2014

REVEL, Atlantic City, New Jersey

- Developed responsive front-end web applications that replicate design mockups.
- Achieved cross browser compatibility and performance.
- Lead intern programmers in acquiring programming methodologies and best practices.

# Programmer

September 2010 - September 2011

GOVERNMENT OF CANADA, DEFENCE MINISTRY, Montréal, Quebec

- Assisted in migrating order management application from MS Access to .NET.
- Created data table and stored procedures with MS SQL Server 2005.
- Helped reduce loss in the warehouse from 20% to 10%.
- Reduced conflicts risks and increase productivity of staff as acknowledged by managers.

#### **Technical support**

March 2006 - March 2009

ADP, Roseland, New-Jersey

- Managed linux operating systems, website maintenance and update.
- Reduced response time to customer requests by providing quick answers to their questions.

# Education

Computer Programmer, Associate, Bois de Boulogne College, Montréal, Québec

Front-End Web Developer, Nanodegree, Udacity, Mountain View California:

Courses Taken: Intro to HTML and CSS, Responsive Web Design Fundamentals, Responsive Images, Version Control, JavaScript Basics, Intro to jQuery, Hosting Projects with GitHub Pages, Object-Oriented JavaScript, HTML5 Canvas, Website Performance Optimization, Browser Rendering Optimization, Intro to AJAX, JavaScript Design Patterns, JavaScript Testing.